# **Austin Schaffer**

(703) 258 9423 | schaffer.austin.t@gmail.com <u>github.com/AustinTSchaffer</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/AustinTSchaffer</u> | <u>linktr.ee/AustinTSchaffer</u> Last Updated - March 15, 2024

## Statement of Purpose

I am a software engineer with 8 years of professional experience. I am most proficient with cloud software, but I also have experience in many other domains including DevOps, edge computing, desktop applications, system administration, and application support. I love working with large volumes of data. I love designing the architecture for new applications. I love investigating issues with systems, proposing solutions, and implementing those solutions. My aim is to increase reliability, lower cost, build cool things, and learn everything that I can.

### Work Experience

# **Senior Software Engineer**

Cloud Platform - Everactive

September 2021 - Current

TimescaleDB, PostgreSQL, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Kotlin, Go, Typescript, Python, GitLab, Terraform, Docker, MQTT

Multi-faceted cross-team software engineering role, from edge to cloud computing

Design, architect, and develop real-time data streaming infrastructure for batteryless IoT devices

Develop cloud-native distributed applications comprising REST APIs, microservices, message gueues, and DBs

Routinely investigate the health and cost of data ingest and storage, and implement improvements

Routinely investigate performance issues with production TimescaleDB SQL queries for time-series data

Routinely investigate issues with LTE Ubuntu Core gateways deployed at customer sites, using Tailscale

Designed and built a battery-powered air-gapped field tool for flashing sensor firmware using a Raspberry Pi

Designed and implemented a real-time data egress service, supporting both HTTP and MQTT

Designed and built an airgapped version of our cloud software

#### Infrastructure Engineer (DevOps)

Datascience (DSCI) - Merkle Inc.

April 2020 - September 2021 1 year, 6 months

AWS (EC2, AMIs, Lambda, EMR, S3, IAM), Python/Anaconda, Linux, Bitbucket, Docker, Terraform, Packer

AWS admin and DevOps resource for Merkle's data science team

Managed infrastructure in AWS using Terraform and Bitbucket Pipelines

Deployed Python data science workloads to EC2 instances and EMR clusters

Developed Python packages for interfacing with vendor systems including AWS and Snowflake

Improved the team's dependency management systems using Poetry, simplifying conda environments

Maintained an EC2 AMI build and release process, keeping dev and prod environments secure and up to date

Worked across teams to ensure secure IAM users, roles, and policies are in place for cross-account access

### **Software Developer**

January 2017 - April 2020

Devgineers - Atlas Systems, Inc.

3 years, 4 months

Python, Git, Docker, Debian Linux, C# (.NET Framework and .NET Core), Linode, Azure, Azure DevOps

Developed ETL pipelines for archival metadata using Python

Provisioned and managed Linux VMs for docker-compose environment deployments

Configured automated build pipelines in Azure Devops

Set up private package registries for Python and C# projects

Trained development and data migration teams on Git, Python, Docker, SQL, and Azure DevOps Build Pipelines Lead developer for Atlas's C# .NET Framework applications

Provided technical support for Atlas's core products, plugins, and hosted services

Researched and developed automated workflows for Development and IT processes

#### Software Developer I - Quick Response Team (QRT)

Ferguson IT - Ferguson Enterprises, Inc.

Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

5 months

Provided tier-3 technical support to IT staff and warehouse employees Researched problems with in-house WMS, developed in uniBasic Resolved issues with production data, through direct database queries

# **Austin Schaffer**

(703) 258 9423 | schaffer.austin.t@gmail.com github.com/AustinTSchaffer | linkedin.com/in/AustinTSchaffer | linktr.ee/AustinTSchaffer

Last Updated - March 15, 2024

#### Education

## Georgia Tech (Georgia Institute of Technology) - College of Computing

August 2022 - Currently Enrolled

M.S. Computer Science (OMSCS)

Currently pursuing an M.S in Computer Science through Georgia Tech's online masters program (OMSCS)

## **Christopher Newport University**

August 2011 - May 2016 cum laude, 3.57 GPA

B.S. Computer Science, Computer Engineering

CNU Honors Program

Vice President, Upsilon Pi Epsilon, CS Honor Society

PCSE Lab Assistant and CS Tutor

#### Certifications

Microsoft - Programming in C# (Exam 70-483)

(ISC)<sup>2</sup> - Certified Secure Software Lifecycle Professional (CSSLP)

April 2017

## Volunteer Experience

## **Software Development and DevOps Volunteer**

March 2021 - November 2023

Code4Cville - Code4America

Currently engaged in a project to perform sentiment analysis over a collection of public comments, all pertaining

to a new guidance put forth by Virginia's executive branch

Participate in community projects for Code4Cville's pro-bono consulting division

Oracle Cloud administrator for various teams and projects

Mitigate cloud security concerns for Code4Cville's Oracle VPC and Linux instances

Manage a Jupyterhub instance for ongoing data science projects

Web scraping, data engineering, NLP+ML, DevOps, consulting

#### Internship Experience

#### Intern - Preserving and Analyzing Airborne Science Observational Data Project

Jan 2016 - Jun 2016

NASA Langley Research Center

Worked with NASA data scientists to improve ICARTT data merge process

Developed an XML schema to configure data merge process

# **Incident Response Intern - Swisslog STAR Team**

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Swisslog Logistics - Swisslog Warehouse and Distribution Services

4 months

6 months

Provided technical support to Swisslog clients

### **Project Manager - CNU Mobile Applications Development Team**

May 2013 - Aug 2014

Information Technology Services - Christopher Newport University

1 year, 4 months

Developed CNU's first official mobile application using Telerik AppBuilder (HTML, JS, CSS)

### Skills

Programming - Python, Kotlin, Golang, Typescript/Javascript, C# (.NET Core), SQL, HTML/CSS, Lua, F#, Java Tools - Git, Terraform, Docker/Containers, Linux, Markdown, Bash/Zsh, Packer, VSCode, PyCharm, IntelliJ Infrastructure - PostgreSQL, TimescaleDB, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Kafka Connect, RabbitMQ, Prometheus, Docker Service Providers - AWS, Aiven, Auth0, GitLab, GitHub, Azure, Linode, Digital Ocean, Oracle Cloud Duties Performed - Architecture Design, Code Reviews, Semantic Versioning, Dependency Management, Production Support, Application Forensics, Database Administration, System Administration, CI/CD